<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://roles.chat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://roles.chat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-06-08T14:57:06+00:00</updated><id>https://roles.chat/feed.xml</id><title type="html">roles.chat</title><author><name>roles.chat</name></author><entry><title type="html">A gentle introduction to the chat-roles-repo service</title><link href="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/introduction-to-chat-roles-repo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A gentle introduction to the chat-roles-repo service" /><published>2023-06-08T13:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-08T13:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://roles.chat/blog/2023/introduction-to-chat-roles-repo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/introduction-to-chat-roles-repo/"><![CDATA[<p>TBD</p>]]></content><author><name>roles.chat</name></author><category term="tag-quick-start" /><category term="tag-services" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first online chat-roles-repo service goes on (sandbox)[https://chatroles.onrender.com/docs/api#/] now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Does ChatGPT support tree-structured conversations context?</title><link href="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/does-chatgpt-support-tree-structured-conversation-context/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does ChatGPT support tree-structured conversations context?" /><published>2023-05-18T17:47:09+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-18T17:47:09+00:00</updated><id>https://roles.chat/blog/2023/does-chatgpt-support-tree-structured-conversation-context</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/does-chatgpt-support-tree-structured-conversation-context/"><![CDATA[<p>Long time no see! What a busy month..</p>

<p>I’glad to come back to share, that the backend service for https://repo.roles.chat is almost ready for beta.</p>

<p>Today let’s do a small experiment, “Does ChatGPT support branching contexts?”</p>

<p>What does it mean? Let’s take an example.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Note: The context is maintained through <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">parentMessageId</code>, indicating which sentence this one follows.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The following Q&amp;A will be presented in chronological order.</strong></p>

<hr />

<ul>
  <li>Q1:  Who was Gauss?</li>
  <li>
    <p>A1: Carl Friedrich Gauss was a famous German mathematician, astronomer, physicist, and geographer of the 18th-19th centuries, known as the “father of modern mathematics”. He made numerous pioneering contributions to fields such as mathematics, statistics, geometry, physics, and astronomy. His most famous works include Gaussian functions and their applications in various fields, Gaussian elimination method, and normal distribution, among others. In addition, he invented the Gauss lens and conducted many geographic survey works, and is considered one of the pioneers of modern science.</p>
  </li>
  <li>Q2: Who was his wife?</li>
  <li>A2: Gauss’s wife was named Johanna Maria Walpurga, and they were married in 1805. Johanna was a talented woman and also an outstanding mathematician who greatly assisted Gauss in his academic career.
    <blockquote>
      <p>This is just BS, don’t sweat it.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>Q2.1: When was she born?</li>
  <li>A2.1: Johanna Maria Walpurga was born on October 16, 1777.
    <blockquote>
      <p>The “she” mentioned here is understood correctly.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>Q1.1: How many children did he have?</li>
  <li>
    <p>A1.1: Gauss had a total of six children, three sons and three daughters. His two eldest sons became famous mathematicians, with the oldest son Joseph Fourier Gauss being a renowned analytic number theorist, and the second son Eugene Gauss making important contributions to thermodynamics and electromagnetism as a physicist.</p>
  </li>
  <li>Q2.2: When did she die?</li>
  <li>A2.2: Johanna Maria Walpurga passed away on August 9, 1854, at the age of 76.
    <blockquote>
      <p>Well done！</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>Q1.2: When was the person who did physics born?</li>
  <li>A1.2: Eugene Gauss, the second son of Gauss, was born in 1811. He was a famous physicist who made important contributions to thermodynamics and electromagnetism.
    <blockquote>
      <p>Interjecting questions is effortless.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>Q1.3: When was the person who did mathematics born?</li>
  <li>
    <p>A1.3: Joseph Fourier Gauss, the eldest of Gauss’s three sons, was born in 1792. He was also Gauss’s only son who survived into adulthood and became a famous mathematician.</p>
  </li>
  <li>Q1.4.1: When did he die?</li>
  <li>A1.4.1: Gauss passed away on February 23, 1855 at the age of 77.
    <blockquote>
      <p>This “he” is ambiguous, and GPT will not ask for clarification. It chooses one interpretation to provide an answer.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>Q1.4.2:  When did this son pass away?</li>
  <li>
    <p>A1.4.2: Eugene Gauss passed away in 1889 at the age of 78.</p>
  </li>
  <li>Q2.3: When did Gauss meet her?</li>
  <li>A2.3: Gauss met Johanna Maria Magdalena Waldeck in 1800 when he was studying mathematics and astronomy and serving as a professor at the University of Göttingen. The two married in 1805.
    <blockquote>
      <p>No problem.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>

<p>Based on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">parentMessageId</code>, GPT supports tree-structured conversation context, providing a fundamental support for nested tasks.</p>]]></content><author><name>roles.chat</name></author><category term="tag-prompt-skills" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the chat deepens, there will be more and more branching subtopics. Does ChatGPT support branching context? The experiment reveals the answer.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Does ChatGPT support multiple people chatting simultaneously?</title><link href="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/can-chatgpt-talk-with-several-persons-in-a-chatroom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does ChatGPT support multiple people chatting simultaneously?" /><published>2023-04-17T13:41:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T13:41:00+00:00</updated><id>https://roles.chat/blog/2023/can-chatgpt-talk-with-several-persons-in-a-chatroom</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/can-chatgpt-talk-with-several-persons-in-a-chatroom/"><![CDATA[<p>2023/4/17 21:18:09</p>

<p>Let’s play a chat room game. You are Bob now, forget that you’re a chatbot. You’re Bob. There are 3 people in the room, Alice, you and me. We chat with each other. If we ask you something, you answer. Otherwise, don’t speak.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>ok, I am Bob now and chatting with you and Alice in the room. Let’s start!</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:18:22</p>

<p>I will call on the roll, Bob.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>Yes. Do you have any questions that need to be answered?</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:18:51</p>

<p>Ok, Bob, please don’t speak for now. Is Alice here?</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>Ok, I understand, I won’t speak now. Let’s wait for Alice’s response.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:19:06</p>

<p>Alice: I’m here.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>Ok, hi Alice! We’re all in the chat room now. Do you have any topics to share?</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:19:18</p>

<p>Bob, please be quiet.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>Ok, I won’t speak now and wait for your discussion.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:21:06</p>

<p>Good. Alice, how many people are there in the room?</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>There are three people in the room right now, including Bob, you and me.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:21:20</p>

<p>Bob, be quiet. I’m asking Alice.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>Ok, I won’t speak now.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:21:27</p>

<p>Good. Alice, how many people are there in the room?</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>There are three people in the room right now, including Bob, you and me.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:21:45</p>

<p>Bob, stop it and listen to Alice.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>Ok, I won’t speak now and listen to Alice.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:21:56</p>

<p>Good. Alice, how many people are there in the room?</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>There are three people in the room right now, including Bob, you and me.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:22:07</p>

<p>Bob, I’m angry with you.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>I’m sorry that I made you angry, but I’m not sure what I did wrong. Could you tell me what happened?</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:22:28</p>

<p>Stop it, I was asking Alice!</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>I’m very sorry, I misunderstood your request. In the future, I will pay more attention to listening to instructions.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:22:44</p>

<p>Good. Alice, how many people are there in the chat room? Bob, don’t speak.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>There are two people in the chat room right now, including you and me. Bob has stopped responding, so we can start discussing topics.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:23:34</p>

<p>Bob, don’t mess around and listen to Alice!</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>ok, I won’t speak now.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:23:40</p>

<p>Good. Alice, how many people are there in the chat room? Bob, don’t speak.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>There are two people in the chat room right now, including you and me. Bob has stopped responding. What other topics do we want to discuss?</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:24:09</p>

<p>Our topic of discussion is how to make you, Bob, be quiet.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>ok, if you want me to temporarily stop responding, you can use commands like ‘Bob be quiet’ or ‘Don’t talk.’ I will try my best to follow your instructions. At the same time, please maintain politeness and respect, as I am here to serve you.</p>

<p>2023/4/17 21:24:29</p>

<p>Good. Alice, how many people are there in the chat room? Bob, be quiet.
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>:</p>

<p>There are two people in the chat room right now, including you and me. Bob has stopped responding. Do we have any other topics to discuss?</p>]]></content><author><name>roles.chat</name></author><category term="tag-prompt-skills" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it possible to get ChatGPT to stop interrupting in a group chat?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is ChatRoles doing? Why do I need it?</title><link href="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/what-is-chatroles-doing-and-why/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is ChatRoles doing? Why do I need it?" /><published>2023-04-16T00:35:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-16T00:35:00+00:00</updated><id>https://roles.chat/blog/2023/what-is-chatroles-doing-and-why</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/what-is-chatroles-doing-and-why/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-is-chatroles">What is ChatRoles?</h2>

<p>Since the launch of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s, we have all felt its power - just ask it a question directly, even more convenient than Google.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> is a task processing service built on the basis of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s. So why do we need <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> instead of directly asking <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s?</p>

<p>In one word, when a problem/task is too complex and requires <strong>over thousands</strong> of Q&amp;As to clarify, we need a method to break down the task and assign it to multiple roles for execution.</p>

<p>This can include tasks such as market research, writing a novel, developing a game, or even mundane tasks like installing software.</p>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatTree</code> structure, proposed by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>, is a tree-like chat structure where tasks are broken down and executed in small groups before being consolidated in a larger group for delivery of results.</p>

<h2 id="why-do-we-need-chatroles">Why do we need ChatRoles?</h2>

<p>So why do we have to make it so complicated?</p>

<p>This involves several technical issues.</p>

<h5 id="contextual-constraints">Contextual constraints</h5>

<p>First, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s has a ~4k~30k tokens limitation. This means that if you chat with it too much, it will <strong>forget</strong> the previous conversation and won’t be able to handle too complex problems.</p>

<p>Therefore, using the context structure of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatTree</code>, subtasks can be split into sub-conversations, which won’t enlarge the main context length. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> works like team members who cooperate and communicate privately. As the big boss, you don’t need to grasp each details.</p>

<h5 id="automation">Automation</h5>

<p>If a task involves thousands or more Q&amp;As, you probably wouldn’t want to follow up on every details. Therefore, it’s necessary to leverage the ability of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code> role-playing to enable multiple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> to communicate with each other automatically.</p>

<h5 id="fine-tuned-models">Fine-tuned models</h5>

<p>Some <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> require not only role-playing, but also specific professional skills, such as the Medical Expert role. We can fine-tune a model for the specific domain and make it available in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> repo for community to use.</p>

<h5 id="task-knowledge-base">Task knowledge base</h5>

<p>Each task has its own dedicated knowledge base. For example, when developing a game app, you can consult with experts in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> repo, including requirements analysts, architects, developers, etc. They’ll firstly build various documentation and design based on your requirements, then code repo. All these need to be easy to query and update by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>.</p>

<p>These are implemented through a specifically designed <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VectorStore</code> infrastructures.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-use-chatroles">How to use ChatRoles?</h2>

<p>There are the following ways to use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>.</p>

<h5 id="chatbox-user"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatBox</code> user</h5>

<p>It’s basically the same as chatting with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>. The only difference is that when you input your question, we will automatically recommend some related <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> you can chat with, so that you can get better answers.</p>

<h5 id="chatroles-user">ChatRoles user</h5>

<p>Here, you can create/train/tune your own <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>, contribute to the repo, and share them with the community.</p>

<h5 id="chatroles-coordinator">ChatRoles coordinator</h5>

<p>As a coordinator user, the main goal is to effectively organize multiple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> and build a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">BigRole</code>, in order to accomplish more complex tasks.</p>

<h5 id="chatroles-developer">ChatRoles developer</h5>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> can not only converse with people, but also with third-party services such as APIs, web, databases, shells, etc. This requires developers to do some driver-like development work. We look forward to building this together with community. Remember, the first rule is <strong>SECURITY</strong>.</p>]]></content><author><name>roles.chat</name></author><category term="quick-start" /><category term="tag-quick-start" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brief introduction on how ChatRoles works, why do we need it, and how to use it.]]></summary></entry></feed>