<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://roles.chat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://roles.chat/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-04-17T13:54:56+00:00</updated><id>https://roles.chat/feed.xml</id><title type="html">roles.chat</title><author><name>roles.chat</name></author><entry><title type="html">What is ChatRoles doing? Why do I need it?</title><link href="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/what-is-chatroles-doing-and-why/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is ChatRoles doing? Why do I need it?" /><published>2023-04-16T00:35:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-16T00:35:00+00:00</updated><id>https://roles.chat/blog/2023/what-is-chatroles-doing-and-why</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://roles.chat/blog/2023/what-is-chatroles-doing-and-why/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-is-chatroles">What is ChatRoles?</h2>

<p>Since the launch of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s, we have all felt its power - just ask it a question directly, even more convenient than Google.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> is a task processing service built on the basis of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s. So why do we need <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> instead of directly asking <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s?</p>

<p>In one word, when a problem/task is too complex and requires <strong>over thousands</strong> of Q&amp;As to clarify, we need a method to break down the task and assign it to multiple roles for execution.</p>

<p>This can include tasks such as market research, writing a novel, developing a game, or even mundane tasks like installing software.</p>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatTree</code> structure, proposed by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>, is a tree-like chat structure where tasks are broken down and executed in small groups before being consolidated in a larger group for delivery of results.</p>

<h2 id="why-do-we-need-chatroles">Why do we need ChatRoles?</h2>

<p>So why do we have to make it so complicated?</p>

<p>This involves several technical issues.</p>

<h5 id="contextual-constraints">Contextual constraints</h5>

<p>First, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>s has a ~4k~30k tokens limitation. This means that if you chat with it too much, it will <strong>forget</strong> the previous conversation and won’t be able to handle too complex problems.</p>

<p>Therefore, using the context structure of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatTree</code>, subtasks can be split into sub-conversations, which won’t enlarge the main context length. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> works like team members who cooperate and communicate privately. As the big boss, you don’t need to grasp each details.</p>

<h5 id="automation">Automation</h5>

<p>If a task involves thousands or more Q&amp;As, you probably wouldn’t want to follow up on every details. Therefore, it’s necessary to leverage the ability of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code> role-playing to enable multiple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> to communicate with each other automatically.</p>

<h5 id="fine-tuned-models">Fine-tuned models</h5>

<p>Some <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> require not only role-playing, but also specific professional skills, such as the Medical Expert role. We can fine-tune a model for the specific domain and make it available in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> repo for community to use.</p>

<h5 id="task-knowledge-base">Task knowledge base</h5>

<p>Each task has its own dedicated knowledge base. For example, when developing a game app, you can consult with experts in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> repo, including requirements analysts, architects, developers, etc. They’ll firstly build various documentation and design based on your requirements, then code repo. All these need to be easy to query and update by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>.</p>

<p>These are implemented through a specifically designed <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">VectorStore</code> infrastructures.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-use-chatroles">How to use ChatRoles?</h2>

<p>There are the following ways to use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>.</p>

<h5 id="chatbox-user"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatBox</code> user</h5>

<p>It’s basically the same as chatting with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatGPT</code>. The only difference is that when you input your question, we will automatically recommend some related <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> you can chat with, so that you can get better answers.</p>

<h5 id="chatroles-user">ChatRoles user</h5>

<p>Here, you can create/train/tune your own <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code>, contribute to the repo, and share them with the community.</p>

<h5 id="chatroles-coordinator">ChatRoles coordinator</h5>

<p>As a coordinator user, the main goal is to effectively organize multiple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> and build a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">BigRole</code>, in order to accomplish more complex tasks.</p>

<h5 id="chatroles-developer">ChatRoles developer</h5>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ChatRoles</code> can not only converse with people, but also with third-party services such as APIs, web, databases, shells, etc. This requires developers to do some driver-like development work. We look forward to building this together with community. Remember, the first rule is <strong>SECURITY</strong>.</p>]]></content><author><name>roles.chat</name></author><category term="quick-start" /><category term="tag-quick-start" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A brief introduction on how ChatRoles works, why do we need it, and how to use it.]]></summary></entry></feed>